<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Rpokle on Saitech</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rpokle/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Rpokle on Saitech</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rpokle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Liminal space</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/liminal-space/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/liminal-space/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/1.png" alt="Featured image of post Liminal space" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why Abandoned Worlds Feel So Strange Yet So Beautiful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something unsettling yet mesmerizing about wandering through abandoned video game worlds. The concrete jungles streaked with rusting steel beams—decaying remnants of past lives—feel like places you’ve been to in dreams or glimpsed in the corner of your eye, even though you know you never have. They evoke a strange pull, a tension between comfort and alienation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ve finally put my finger on why these spaces captivate me so much. It’s the uncanny valley, not in the traditional sense of humanoid robots or photorealistic characters, but in the way they resemble real places yet feel slightly&amp;hellip; off. This idea ties closely to liminal spaces—those eerie transitional zones that feel stuck in time and evoke a profound sense of stillness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These virtual environments strip away the noise of human activity, leaving behind only echoes. There are no distractions, no crowds, no bustling NPCs. It’s just you and the hollow architecture of forgotten places. And surprisingly, there’s a niche in gaming dedicated to this: experiences that aren’t games in the traditional sense, but rather walking simulators that immerse you in these desolate worlds.
The Lure of Silence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love most are the games that keep interference to a minimum. Horror elements can sometimes lean too heavily on jump scares or tension, but the quiet ones—the ones that let you simply exist—are the ones that stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take BABBDI, for example. This short exploration game completely captured my imagination. Its description is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;BABBDI is a short, first-person exploration experience with light narrative and platforming elements.
Visit the town of BABBDI, a forsaken district in the outer ring of the megalopolis. Meet its inhabitants and discover how to escape.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this doesn’t tell you what it feels like to play. Wandering through the desolate streets of BABBDI, surrounded by muted gray tones, I found myself immersed in its quiet melancholy. The air felt heavy with stories untold, whispers of lives once lived but now absent. There’s no rush to leave, no immediate threat to overcome—just the haunting beauty of a forgotten place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a game that lingers in your mind long after you’ve played it, much like a dream you can’t quite shake. I’ve promised myself I’ll return to BABBDI one day when I’m in the right mood, just to stroll through its streets again and let its atmosphere wash over me.
More Worlds to Wander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BABBDI is far from the only game that offers this kind of experience. Over time, I’ve stumbled upon others, each with its own take on liminal beauty. Some I’ve played, and some are still waiting for the right moment to pull me in. Here’s a list of games I’m keeping in mind for my next exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Insert games you’ve discovered—be sure to share their unique vibe!)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These experiences remind me that games don’t always need grand narratives or complex mechanics to make an impact. Sometimes, the simplest thing—a quiet walk through an empty, crumbling world—is all it takes to feel profoundly connected to something beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next time that strange, reflective mood strikes, I’ll know where to go. Maybe you’ll find yourself in one of these worlds, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take BABBDI, for example. This short exploration game completely captured my imagination. Its description is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;BABBDI is a short, first-person exploration experience with light narrative and platforming elements.
Visit the town of BABBDI, a forsaken district in the outer ring of the megalopolis. Meet its inhabitants and discover how to escape.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this doesn’t tell you what it feels like to play. Wandering through the desolate streets of BABBDI, surrounded by muted gray tones, I found myself immersed in its quiet melancholy. The air felt heavy with stories untold, whispers of lives once lived but now absent. There’s no rush to leave, no immediate threat to overcome—just the haunting beauty of a forgotten place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a game that lingers in your mind long after you’ve played it, much like a dream you can’t quite shake. I’ve promised myself I’ll return to BABBDI one day when I’m in the right mood, just to stroll through its streets again and let its atmosphere wash over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lemaitre-bros.itch.io/babbdi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Babbdi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/265690/NaissanceE/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NaissanceE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://eugenio-lopez.itch.io/concrete-paths&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mikeklubnika.itch.io/concrete-tremor&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moshelinke.itch.io/fugue-in-void&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://umbrella-isle.itch.io/222am&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1699480/KLETKA/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;asd&#34;&gt;asd
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
